## ŁUKASZ LESZKO

## ML Engineer

Preferred locations: Warsaw, remotely or short-term abroad.

Student at the University of Warsaw with a strong background

in competitive programming and 1 year of professional soft-

ware development experience. Knowledgeable about applying machine learning to real-world projects, such as **Git Optim** 

and QUMAM. Solid foundation in mathematics and driven to

## SKILLS

+48 ...

Languages: Python, C++, Rust, Haskell, TypeScript, Java

ML: PyTorch, Transformers, ONNX, scikit-learn, NumPy,

leszkolukasz

leszkolukasz

Polars

leszko.lucas@gmail.com

🖍 lukasz.leszko.dev

Web: React, Django, FastAPI, Spring

DevOps: Docker, Google Cloud, Nix

# PROJECTS

SUMMARY

#### **Git Optim**

apply technical expertise to high-impact solutions.

Developed as part of my Bachelor's thesis in Computer Science. Web application that utilizes Large Language Models (**LLMs**) to monitor CI/CD pipelines for warnings and errors in job logs. Upon detection, it automatically creates pull request with suggested fixes.

Python, Accelerate, Llama.cpp, ChromaDB, TypeScript, Next.js, FastAPI

#### QUMAM

Learning platform for managing math courses and students. It offers rich UI for creating courses and exercises, as well as a student portal for tracking progress. Includes **LLM** capabilities like math task generation from image.

Python, LiteLLM, OpenAI, TypeScript, React, Django, PostgreSQL

Many more projects are available in my portfolio and GitHub profile.

#### EXPERIENCE -

### 7/2024 - 10/2024 Junior Software Engineer

RadCode, Warsaw

- Worked as a contractor for an American startup founded by a Forbes 30 Under 30 laureate.
- · Developed a Web3 protocol with goal to innovate decentralized finance (DeFi).

TypeScript, Solidity, ReactJS, Hardhat, Vite, GraphQL

#### 7/2023 - 7/2024

### **Junior Software Engineer**

Cognizant, Warsaw

## Project 1

- Acted as a project lead, actively contributing to the development of an internal web application using the Kanban methodology.
- Successfully deployed version 2.0 of the application.

Java, Kotlin, Spring, Jenkins, TypeScript, ReactJS, Vite, MongoDB, SendGrid

#### Project 2

- Worked as contractor for American company.
- Refactored and optimized the application's codebase to adhere to clean code standards.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Integrated Kafka using outbox pattern for efficient message queuing and processing.

Java, Spring, GitHub Actions, TypeScript, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, Kafka

### **EDUCATION**

### 2024 - current M.Sc. in Machine Learning

University of Warsaw

Elective courses: Data Mining, Engineering Distributed Infrastructure, Robot Learning

2022 - current

### **B.Sc. in Mathematics**

University of Warsaw

Relevant courses: Statistical Data Analysis, Machine Learning (GenAI)

2021 - 2024

## B.Sc. in Computer Science

University of Warsaw

Relevant courses: Machine Learning (classical methods)
Thesis: Gitoptim - a tool for automating programmer's work using large language models

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Distinction in the 1st round of the 28th Polish Olympiad in Informatics
- Finalist of the 4th edition of the Jagiellonian Mathematics Tournament
- · Tutored two participants of Polish Olympiad in Informatics. One reached international level.

### LANGUAGES

English - B2/C1 (FCE Certificate), Polish - native

### INTERESTS

- · Open source: contributed to LibreOffice
- Programming languages (compilers, language design)
- Linux